I just was instantly captured by the sensory aspects of the game.
我一下子就被这项游戏带来的感官体验吸引住了。
The way the tiles look, the way they feel, you know, they're cool and smooth and heavy.
无论是麻将牌的外观，还是摸起来的感觉——它们凉凉的、光滑而且有分量。
There's nothing like the sound of Mahjong tiles as you mix or wash them.
没有什么声音能比得上洗牌时麻将牌相互碰撞的声音。
American Mahjong comes in many different sizes, tons of colors and designs.
美式麻将有许多不同的尺寸、颜色和设计。
I do have a special set that is a Wizard of Oz theme.
我确实有一副很特别的麻将，是以《绿野仙踪》为主题的。
The Glitterville set has cakes, cookies, and donuts for flowers.
Glitterville那副牌用蛋糕、曲奇和甜甜圈来代替花牌上的图案。
When I come up with the design, I try to brand the contemporary illustration with the delegates of the heritage craftsmanship.
当我构思设计时，我会尝试把当代插画与传统工艺的代表性元素结合起来。
It's a dying art, and I wanted something special to be in my collection that we would have forever once the carvers are no longer around.
这是一门正在消失的艺术，所以我希望收藏一件特别的作品，即使未来这些雕刻师都不在了，我们也可以永远保留下来。
Mahjong is a game that is played with tiles that is similar to the game of Rummy, where you choose random tiles and try to complete a winning hand.
麻将是一种使用牌块进行的游戏，与拉米牌有些相似：玩家随机选择牌，并努力组成一副获胜牌型。
There are three suits that you play with.
游戏中有三种花色。
The Dots that are typically round and look like a dot.
第一种是筒子，图案通常是圆形的，看起来像圆点。
The Cracks, which stands for Chinese characters, and the Bams, which are usually green and stands for bamboo.
第二种是万子，代表汉字；第三种是条子，通常是绿色的，代表竹子。
There are also some other tiles that help you build your hand.
还有一些其他的牌可以帮助你组成牌型。
They would be the Winds, the Flowers, and the Dragons.
它们分别是风牌、花牌和箭牌。
In American Mahjong, we also use Jokers, so I ask them specifically to make Jokers for my Hong Kong set.
美式麻将还会使用百搭牌，所以我特意请他们为我的香港麻将制作了百搭牌。
I really love the one dot or one circle because there is so much variation that's possible within this sphere of design.
我特别喜欢一筒，因为在这个圆形图案的设计范围内，可以做出非常多不同的变化。
The One Bam, also known as the Bird Bam.
一条，也被称为"鸟条"。
Heritage from one-won because you can really find the calligraphy inside the depth of the stroke.
一万尤其能体现传统，因为你确实可以在笔画的深浅之中看到书法的韵味。
Mahjong was first created in the area around Shanghai and the Yangtze River Delta in the mid to late 1800s.
麻将最早诞生于上海及长江三角洲一带，时间大约是在19世纪中后期。
Really from the get go, the game was marketed to an American public as an ancient royal game of the Chinese court.
其实从一开始，这款游戏在美国市场上就被宣传成一种源自中国宫廷的古老皇家游戏。
In the 1920s boom, thousands and thousands of sets were made by hand.
在20世纪20年代麻将热潮期间，成千上万副麻将都是手工制作的。
In that process, they also increasingly standardized the designs, but higher end sets, which were made by very, very skilled craftsmen, were carved with often just like a hair's breadth, really delicate scenes.
在这一过程中，麻将牌的设计也越来越标准化；但高端麻将由技艺极其精湛的工匠制作，他们能够在极其细微的空间内雕刻出非常精致的场景。
But once they really start being made exclusively by machine and no longer by hand, that standardization process really takes off.⏩
但是，一旦麻将开始完全由机器生产、不再依赖手工制作，标准化进程便迅速加快了。
Newly-produced hand-carved tiles are really rare and precious these days.
如今，新制作的手工雕刻麻将牌非常稀有而珍贵。
Machine-made tiles often do a great job of mimicking some of the designs, but having that kind of signature detail or style that's really communicated only by hand is just inimitable.
机器制造的麻将牌通常能够很好地模仿某些设计，但是那种只能通过手工呈现的标志性细节和风格，是无法复制的。
The Hong Kong tiles, you can tell by touching and feeling that they are an individual work of art, and the tiles that are produced by the American companies are mass-made and they look like they came out of a machine.
香港麻将牌只要摸一摸、感受一下，就能看出每一块都是独立的艺术品；而美国公司生产的麻将牌是批量制造的，看起来就像直接从机器里出来的一样。
They're very different from American Mahjong.
它们与美式麻将牌非常不同。
They're chunky and big, and they're not elaborately decorated.
它们厚实而且尺寸较大，装饰也没有那么繁复。
You don't use the racks that we use in American Mahjong, and you just set them on the table.
玩这种麻将时，不会使用美式麻将里的牌架，而是直接把牌立在桌面上。
But I like that they're different and unique, and most people don't have them.
但我喜欢它们的与众不同和独特之处，而且大多数人都没有这样的麻将牌。
I took my first lesson in August or September of 2025.
我在2025年8月或9月上了第一节麻将课。
I kept seeing things online about this game, but I knew nothing about it, so I began researching Mahjong and I discovered that many tiles were originally made in Hong Kong, and so I decided to go on this goose chase of getting myself a set from Hong Kong, hand-carved.
我不断在网上看到关于这款游戏的内容，但对它一无所知，于是开始研究麻将。我发现很多麻将牌最初都是在香港制作的，因此决定展开一场漫长而曲折的搜寻，为自己买一副香港手工雕刻的麻将。
Somehow, after all my digging, I found a lady on Instagram and she visited this particular artist, the last female artisan in Hong Kong.
不知怎么，在进行了一番深入搜寻之后，我在 Instagram 上找到了一位女士，而她拜访了这位特别的艺术家——香港最后一位女性麻将雕刻工匠。
After many messages, emails, back and forth, I was sending money to Hong Kong to buy these tiles.
在来来回回发送了许多信息和邮件之后，我终于把钱汇到香港，购买了这副麻将牌。
I really hope that hand-carving tiles continues to exist in an art form.
我真的希望手工雕刻麻将牌能够继续作为一种艺术形式存在下去。
I do think that particularly thanks to a resurgence of interest in Mahjong that's happening globally right now, there is enough of a market that will continue to support artisans who want to continue this craft.
我确实认为，尤其得益于当前全球范围内对麻将兴趣的复兴，市场需求已经足以继续支持那些希望传承这门手艺的工匠。
My favorite parts about playing are the really cute tiles, the setup of the game.
玩麻将时，我最喜欢的是那些非常可爱的牌，以及整个游戏的布置过程。
American Mahjong, it's not just about playing the game, it's about all the aesthetics that go along with it.
美式麻将不只是玩游戏本身，也包括与之相伴的整套审美体验。
A Mahjong tablescape typically involves your mat, your racks, coasters, dice, dishes.
一套麻将桌面布置通常包括桌垫、牌架、杯垫、骰子和小碟子。
There's a whole world out there of people wanting to get their tablescape perfected, and so they go to each other in the group and say, "I have this set of tiles.
外面有一整个群体的人，都希望把自己的麻将桌面布置做到尽善尽美，所以她们会在群组里互相询问："我有这样一副麻将牌。"
What mat and racks would you suggest?" "
你会推荐搭配什么桌垫和牌架？"
Or, "I bought these racks today, what tiles would go with that?"
或者："我今天买了这些牌架，什么样的麻将牌和它搭配比较好？"
What's happening right now is quite new in that some American Mahjong companies the designers are based in the United States, but they're generally being made in China.
当前出现的情况相当新颖：一些美式麻将公司的设计师位于美国，但产品通常是在中国制造的。
They might be playing with references to American Mahjong culture and slang that another person who plays a different kind of Mahjong wouldn't be familiar with.
这些设计可能会巧妙运用美式麻将文化和俚语中的典故，而玩其他类型麻将的人可能并不熟悉这些内容。
I'm not a Mahjong purist.
我并不是一个麻将纯粹主义者。
I started this thing just six, eight months ago, so I love all the new designs, but I can understand people who have been playing for 50 years or maybe their grandmother played, it's probably a little odd to see things that aren't the traditional faces on the tiles.
我接触麻将才六到八个月，所以我很喜欢所有这些新设计；但我也能理解那些已经打了50年麻将，或者祖母也打过麻将的人。看到牌面上出现不属于传统图案的东西，对他们来说可能确实有些奇怪。
We are reaching a point where it's a fair question to ask if a game is played with unrecognizable equipment, is it actually the same game still, or has it changed to the point of becoming something else?
我们正在走到这样一个阶段：如果一款游戏使用的器具已经让人无法辨认，那么合理的问题是，它是否仍然是原来的游戏，还是已经发生了巨大变化，变成了另一种东西？
I would be sad if American Mahjong really became fully divorced from a global context of Mahjong, because I think that ability to connect across difference is quite powerful and something we really need.
如果美式麻将真的完全脱离了全球麻将文化的整体语境，我会感到难过，因为我认为这种跨越差异、建立联系的能力非常有力量，也是我们真正需要的东西。
I try to brand the contemporary art, okay, with my father, traditional way of hand crafting.
我努力把当代艺术与我父亲传统的手工制作方式结合起来。
Mahjong is really very important for my family.
麻将对我的家庭来说真的非常重要。
I witnessed the up and down, the disappearing of such kind of traditional game among people during the 2000s, so I build up Karen Aruba Art because I keep thinking, can I do something related to the art or craft that can be keep for the long term?
我亲眼见证了这种传统游戏在21世纪初经历的兴衰，以及它逐渐从大众生活中消失的过程。因此，我创立了 Karen Aruba Art，因为我一直在想：我能否做一些与这门艺术或工艺相关的事情，让它得到长期保存？
I think for Karen Aruba Art, we want to focus on some unique handcrafting work, so I try to use the illustration laser-engraved, but then my father still handcrafting on some traditional Mahjong patterns.
对于 Karen Aruba Art，我们希望专注于独特的手工艺作品。因此，我会使用激光雕刻来呈现插画，而我的父亲仍然会亲手制作一些传统麻将图案。
When I come up with the design, I try to keep some traditional cultural elements.
当我构思设计时，我会努力保留一些传统文化元素。
For example, I will try to study the background, the history, to understand why people design this way.
例如，我会研究相关背景和历史，以理解过去的人为什么会采用这样的设计方式。
One of the mission of Karen Aruba Art is to keep on training people, but because my father closed the factory, they even lost all their Mahjong tools.
Karen Aruba Art的使命之一就是持续培训新人，但由于我父亲关闭了工厂，他们甚至失去了所有制作麻将的工具。
I realized that if we want to teach people hand crafting, they do not have enough tools.
我意识到，如果我们想教别人手工制作麻将，他们却没有足够的工具可用。
Luckily, my husband's brother, he's also one of the wood craftsmen.
幸运的是，我丈夫的兄弟也是一位木工匠人。
He helped me to recreate few sets, and then we found a factory in Malaysia.
他帮助我重新制作了几套工具，后来我们又在马来西亚找到了一家工厂。
He can recreate the scissors for us.
他可以为我们复刻这些雕刻工具。
So right now we have around eight to five full set of Mahjong-making tools.
所以目前我们大约拥有五到八套完整的麻将制作工具。
I mean, that is quite difficult to pass their professional skills to the next generation because they really need to devote a lot of time in practicing.
我的意思是，把这些专业技艺传给下一代确实非常困难，因为学习者必须投入大量时间练习。
But I do see that my role helped to build up the gap between the next generation and my father, the traditional elderly craftsmanship.
但我的确看到，自己的角色有助于弥合年轻一代与我父亲这一代传统老工匠之间的距离。
If we keep on doing something, I still trust that we can keep on moving on, passing such kind of skills.
只要我们坚持做下去，我仍然相信我们能够继续向前，把这样的技艺传承下去。